Akarsh Bachu

Data Scientist

Skilled in Java, Data Science and Machine Learning with 1.5+ years of experience, Achievements include creating data classification model to predict Turnover of an employee with AUC of 0.88 and Achieved good accuracy on Kaggle Competition Data Sets.



bachu.akarsh@gmail.com

7729862404

Hyderabad, India

akarsh.netlify.com

linkedin.com/in/akarshbachu in

github.com/akarshbachu

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist ADP India Pvt Ltd

10/2018 - Present

Description/Responsibilities

Description: The Product provides Predictive Analytics on HR and Time metrics.

• Environment: Java, Python, Spark, Scala and Oracle Database.

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Performed Machine Learning tasks to predict the turnover of an employee, achieved AUC of 0.88 using XGBoost.
- Generated Insights related to Over Time, Leave and Check-In time of an employee using predictive analytics.

Software Engineer ADP India Pvt Ltd

08/2017 - 09/2018

Hvderabad

74%

Description/Responsibilities

Description: The Product Provides Analytics of various other Products of ADP, Using Dashboards, KPI's (Key Performance Indicators) Benchmarks and Explorers.

Environment: Java, Angular JS, Python, Spark, Scala and Oracle Database.

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Creating KPI's(Key Performance Indicators) using Java and JPA Framework
- Reverting the Defects
- Created a Generic Flow to create a KPI
- The POC(Natural Language Voice Search) created, enables us to query without using business jargon by picking the KPI's, based on the context and displays the corresponding ones on a dashboard.

IOT Intern EXCITE TASK

05/2016 - 06/2016

Achievements/Tasks

 Worked on Arduino and Learnt about IOT, its inventive and innovative scope.

EDUCATION

B.Tech

Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Technology

09/2013 - 05/2017

Course

 Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Donors Choose Application Screening (11/2018 - 12/2018)

It's a Classification problem where our model classifies if the project proposed can be Approved or not, Achieved an AUC of 0.74 using LightGBM.

Netflix Movie Recommendation Engine (08/2018 - 08/2018)

 It's a Machine Learning Model that recommends the movies by analyzing user's previous history.

Stack Overflow Tag Predictor (07/2018 – 07/2018)

 It's a Machine Learning Model, that predicts the suitable tags for the Description/Question given. Achieved precision of 80% and hamming loss of 0.002 using Linear SVM.

Amazon Apparel Recommendation Engine (06/2018 - 06/2018)

It's a Machine Learning Based Model, that Recommends the Similar Products(Apparel's) based on the product selected.

Amazon Review Classification (04/2018 - 04/2018)

It's a Machine Learning project, where the model classifies the reviews as Positive or Negative.

Personal Website (02/2018 - 03/2018)

It's a Personal Portfolio created using HTML and Bootstrap, includes a Chatbot(Virtual Representation of Me).

Heart Connoisseur (05/2016 - 06/2016)

It's an IOT based alarming device built for detecting heart abnormalities that also notifies the pre-chosen contacts for help in the span of an SMS.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Oracle Certified Java Programmer

Oracle Testing Id: OC1731881 (Java SE 8) Hackerrank Algorithm Level 3

Received a Merit certificate from ICSI for presenting 'Heart Connoisseur'(IOT product)